Guide to the Panhellenic Council records, 1938-1996 (bulk 1960-1996) UA.31.21.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Panhellenic Council records
1938-1996 (bulk 1960-1996)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Panhellenic Council
UA.31.21.0001
4.5 Linear Feet
The Duke Panhellenic Association [Panhellenic Council] is the governing body of the 10 National Panhellenic Conference (NPC) sororities on-campus. The collection contains several types of material: the correspondence files date from 1943-1995, the bulk of the Rush information covers 1960 through the mid-1990s, while the minutes and agendas range in date from 1951-1994. The collection as a whole ranges in date from 1938-1996, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960-1996.
4500 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Panhellenic Council records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1978-2002.
Biographical/Historical note
The National Panhellenic Conference was founded in 1902. College chapters of National Panhellenic were the first inter-group organizations on college campuses. Initially, Trinity College and Duke University's fraternities and sororities were governed by their own Panhellenic Council. In 1957, the men's Panhellenic Council became the Interfraternity Council. Sororities remained under the umbrella of the Panhellenic Council. The earliest mention of the Sorority Panhellenic Council at Duke is in the 1913 Chanticleer yearbook. Fannie Kilgo was Chairman, and Catherine C. Thomas was Secretary. The sororities represented within the Council were Kappa Delta and Alpha Delta Phi. According to the 1938 Chanticleer, the Women's Panhellenic Council was founded for the "express purpose of subordinating the individual sorority for the common good of all the sororities." Today, the Panhellenic Council continues to develop and maintain sorority life and inter-sorority relations within the University and promote intellectual accomplishment and sound scholarship.
Scope and Contents note
Contains the Council's constitution, minutes, agendas, financial ledgers, correspondence, sorority files, Rush files, and printed material. The printed material includes several issues of "East Goes Greek," which was given to women interested in rushing on-campus sororities. Information included in the pamphlet included the Greek alphabet, do's and don'ts of rushing, and information on each sorority. The collection also contains material related to the Panhellenic Council's quest for on-campus housing for sororities. The collection dates range from 1938-1996 (bulk 1960-1996).
Related Material
Fraternities and Sororities Collection, 1931-2001
Duke University Archives
Interfraternity Council Records, 1947-2001
Duke University Archives
Douglas M. Knight Records, 1949-1970
Duke University Archives
President H. Keith H. Brodie Records, 1963-1994
Duke University Archives
Alice M. Baldwin Papers, 1863-1961
Duke University Archives
Woman's College Records
Duke University Archives
Alpha Delta Pi. Omicron Chapter Records, 1927-1979
Duke University Archives
Kappa Kappa Gamma. Delta Beta Chapter Records, 1930-1981
Duke University Archives
Kappa Delta. Sigma Delta Chapter Records, 1934-1981
Duke University Archives
Phi Mu. Gamma Epsilon Chapter Records, 1933-1982
Duke University Archives
Pi Beta Phi. North Carolina Beta Chapter Records, 1929-1988
Duke University Archives
Hazing; Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham; Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.); Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.; Duke University -- Students -- Social conditions; Duke University. Panhellenic Council; Panhellenic Council (Duke University); Duke University. Woman’s College -- History; Duke University -- Societies, etc.
- Administrative Records, 1945-1996, 1 boxes
  - Agendas-Executive Council Meetings, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, 1987-1990 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Financial Ledger, 1956-1957, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Financial Ledger, 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - Financial Ledger, 1961-1966 (Box 1)
  - Financial Ledger, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Agendas-Alumni Advisory Board, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Presidents' Meetings, 1951-1957 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Presidents' Meetings, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Presidents' Meetings, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Presidents' Meetings, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Agendas-Presidents' Meetings, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Agendas-Presidents' Meetings, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Agendas-Presidents' Meetings, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Minutes and Agendas-Presidents' Meetings, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Notes-Presidents' Meetings, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Rush Reform Meeting, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Student-Faculty-Administration Council, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Panhel Judie, 1990 RESTRICTED (Box 1)
  - Reports and Evaluations (Rush and Otherwise), 1945-1959 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Evaluations (Rush and Otherwise), 1960-1969 (Box 1)
  - Retreat Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1971-1987 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1987-1991 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Rush, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Rush Advising, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - Rush Advising, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Rush Advising, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Rush Advisor Selection, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
  - Rush Memoranda, 1956-1970 (Box 1)
  - Rush-Open Relations, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Rush Parties, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Rush Rules, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
  - Rush Statistics, 1978-1989 RESTRICTED (Box 1)
  - Rush Timing Reports, 1956-1967 (Box 1)
  - Rush Violations (procedures and cases), 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1956-1969 (Box 1)
- Subject Files, 1938-1995, 1.75 boxes
  - Academic Requirements for Inititiation, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Alcohol, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Chi Omega, 1960-1985 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Delta Pi, 1983-1993 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Epsilon Phi, 1983-1993 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi, 1979-1992 (Box 2)
  - Alpha Phi, 1968, 1973, 1985-1988 (Box 2)
  - Board of Trustees-Rush Evaluation, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Chapter Totals, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
  - Chi Omega, 1985-1992 (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Courses, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence A-D, 1947-1966 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence E-M, 1943-1966 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence N-R, 1952-1966 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence S-Z, 1957-1966 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Deactivation Records, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Deferred Rush, 1947-1968 (Box 2)
  - Delta Delta Delta, 1981-1992 (Box 2)
  - Delta Gamma, 1966-1985 (Box 2)
  - Delta Gamma, 1985-1992 (Box 2)
  - Delta Sigma Theta, 1988-1993 (Box 2)
  - Formal Party List, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Foster Child Sponsorship, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Gamma Alpha Epsilon Honor Society, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Greek System Commentary, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Greek Weekend, 1964, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Inventory of Stored Items, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta, 1972-1993 RESTRICTED (Box 2)
  - Kappa Delta, 1981-1990 RESTRICTED (Box 2)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma, 1981-1994 (Box 2)
  - Membership List, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
  - Membership Statements on Non-Discrimination, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1958-1969 (Box 2)
  - National Panhellenic Conference, 1938-1962 (Box 2)
  - National Panhellenic Conference, 1962-1970 (Box 2)
  - National Panhellenic Conference, 1980-1990 (Box 2)
  - National Panhellenic Conferencen-Annual Report-Duke, 1980-1991 (Box 2)
  - National Student Association (includes J. Edgar Hoover corresp.), 1957-1962 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1954-1969 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1971 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1979 (Box 3)
  - Officers, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Officers, 1972-1991 (Box 3)
  - Panhel Assistantship Program, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Panhel House: A Presentation to the Board of Trustees, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Panhellenic Building (Proposed), 1988 (Box 3)
  - Panhellenic Scholarship Fund, 1948-1949 (Box 3)
  - Panhellenic Sing, 1961-1968 (Box 3)
  - Party Clean-up Incident and Appeal, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Phi Mu, 1982-1987 (Box 3)
  - Photo Composites and Chanticleer, 1965-1970 (Box 3)
  - Pi Beta Phi, 1981-1992 (Box 3)
  - Presidents' Letters for Greek booklet, 1956-1969 (Box 3)
  - Public Relations, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Service and Philanthropy, 1965-1968 (Box 3)
  - Sigma Kappa, 1962-1982 (Box 3)
  - Social Events, 1948-1968 (Box 3)
  - Sorority Expansion, 1976-1984 (Box 3)
  - Sorority Expansion, 1985-1990 (Box 3)
  - Sorority GPA Records, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Sorority House Renovation-Financial Statements, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Sorority Housing-Paperwork, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Sorority Membership Lists, 1964-1970 (Box 3)
  - Sorority Membership Quota, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Sorority System Debate, 1947-1966 (Box 3)
  - Southeastern Panhellenic Conference, 1957-1969 (Box 3)
  - Southeastern Panhellenic Conference, undated (Box 3)
  - Special Events, 1955-1970 (Box 3)
  - Special Situations, 1958-1968 (Box 3)
  - Speeches, 1956-1970 (Box 3)
  - Summer, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Theta Beta Sigma, undated (Box 3)
  - Title IX, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Workshops, 1954-1963 (Box 3)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha, 1983-1991 (Box 3)
  - Zeta Tau Alpha, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
- Printed Matter, 1948-1996, 0.25 boxes
  - Booklet of Information for Social Chairmen, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Brochures, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Duke Panhellenic Newsletter (Vol. I), circa 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Handbooks, 1948-1969 (Box 3)
  - Panhellenic Newsletter, 1955-1969 (Box 3)
  - Take a Peek at a Greek, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
  - The Greek Way, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
- Accession UA2002-0058
  - The Greek Way, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - CAS Standards, Fraternities and Sororities Advising, and Expansion Proposal (Box 3)
  - Panhellenic Council, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Fall 1993 (Box 3)
  - Rush, Spring 1994 (Box 3)
  - Housing Issues, Spring 1994 (Box 3)
  - Fall 1994 Meetings (Box 3)
  - Housing, Spring 1995 (Box 3)
  - Fall 1995 (Box 3)
  - Rush and Progs, Spring 1996 (Box 3)
  - Housing, Spring 1996 (Box 3)
  - Office Space, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Office Space Addendum (Box 3)
  - Letters and News, Fall 1996 (Box 3)
  - Rush, Spring 1997 (Box 3)
  - Fall 1997 Issues (Box 3)
  - Alcohol Policy (Box 3)
  - Panhellenic Constitution, 1996-1997 (Box 3)